慢慢来
Slow.
好痒
That tickles.
那儿也痒
That tickles too.
你欠了多少钱
How much are you in debt?
3万块
Thirty thousand.
3万块什么
Thirty thousand what?
美元
Dollars.
我有个朋友在伊比沙岛开酒吧
A friend of mine has a bar on ibiza.
实际上  还没开张  他要找人合作
Actually, he doesn't have it yet, he needs a partner.
我可以入伙
I could buy in.
只是得要8万块钱
I just need eighty thousand.
欧元吗
Euros?
当然
Of course.
可是你没钱
But you don't have.
有时间  我想见见你们那帮人
I'd like to meet your crowd some time.
我就剩这么点儿了
I'm almost out.
-你能再弄点儿给我吗  -当然
- You can get me more? - Sure.
给他吹个箫或者让他吃片蓝色小药丸
Give him a blow job or have him take a Mr. blue.
我们就是这么对付他们这种人的
That's what we've got them for.
这样很容易就搞定他了
Then he'll be fine.
他出了120欧元
He aid 120 euros.
安琪  出什么事了
Hey, Angel, what's wrong?
不再跟我说"晚上好"了吗
Don't we say good evening anymore?
晚上好
Good evening.
他是个常客
He's a regular,
嫖客不来  你一个子儿都赚不到
If he stops coming, you earn nothing,
更重要的是  我也赚不到钱
And what's more imortant, I earn nothing.
她走了吗
Did she leave?
给我房卡
Give me the card!
-我没看见她  -没事  卡给我
- I didn't see her... - It doesn't matter. the card!
宝贝儿  这次又是怎么回事
Baby, what is it this time?
今天我不干活
I no work today.
咱们走着瞧
We'll see about that.
不要
No.
来吧
C'mon.
今天不要  求你了
Today no, please.
今天我不干活
I not work today.
亮出阴部
Show pussy!
躺那儿  亮出阴部
Go on, lie down. Show pussy!
您的阴部真迷人
You really have a nice pussy.
自己摸摸
You rub a little!
安琪
Well, Angel.
你们相安无事吧
Everything ok?
出来歇口气是吧
A short break...
我想找你谈点事儿
I want to talk to you about something.
说
Yes.
可
But...
不是在这儿谈
Not here.
明天下午我去你住的地方
I'll come by your place tomorrow afternoon?
-行吧  -可以
- Ok? - Yes.
不要和其他姑娘说
Don't say anything to the other girls.
你好啊  甜心
Hello, sweetheart.
多少钱
How much?
先进来  再告诉我你想怎么样吧
Come inside and tell me what you want.
我想干你
I wanna fuck.
再见
Bye.
怎么回事
What this?
你来这儿干啥
What you doing here?
我从秘密入口来的
Secret entrance.
你得马上走  老板要来了
You must leave. Boss coming.
康涅西
Konecny?
他来干啥
What does he want?
他要跟我谈谈
He say talk.
谈啥
About what?
不知道  就是谈谈
I don't know. Talk.
我不知道他要干啥  他说是谈谈
I don't know what he want. He say talk.
谈完了你来我这儿吗
Are you coming over afterwards?
走吧
Go!
是我  安琪
It's me, Angel.
我就来
I coming.
安琪  怎么这么慢
Angel, what's going on?
没穿衣服吗
Weren't you dressed?
我不介意的
That wouldn't have bothered me.
我一直在观察你
I've been observing you.
你是个聪明姑娘
You're a smart girl.
不像别人那么蠢
Not as stuid as the others.
你有目标
You have goals,
生活有计划  我说的对吧
Plans in life, am I right?
我喜欢
I like that.
我一直在考虑如何帮你
And I've been thinking about how to help you.
来  坐
C'mon, sit down.
我手头有些很舒服的公寓
I own a few flats. Nice ones.
客厅  卧室  厨房  啥都有
Living room, bedroom, kitchen, everything, ti to.
你听明白我的话了吗
You follow what I'm saying?
这些公寓有一间
And one of these flats...
可以归在你的名下
Has your name on it.
你可以离开这小破旅馆
You can leave this hotel room behind.
听起来咋样
How does that sound?
多少钱
How much?
不比这儿破地方贵
We'll see, not more than this place.
你知道  我交友甚广
I have friends, you see.
像政客呀  大企业家呀
Politicians, big industry people, etc.
他们有时需要放松一下
Sometimes they want to relax...
就想找个漂亮姑娘
With a pretty girl.
考虑到个人形象
They don't like brothels,
他们不爱去妓院
On account of their image.
他们喜欢私密一点儿
They like it private.
优雅一点儿
Exquisite.
那样你挣的也多
You'd earn more too.
那我不用在灰姑娘做了吗
And I no more work in Cinderella?
咱们拭目以待吧
We'll see.
你做先锋
You will at first.
咱们看看这么做行不行
We'll see how things go.
在妓院接客你有点可惜
You're too special for a brothel.
你有男朋友吗
Do you have a boyfriend?
全靠自己吗
All by yourself?
没人照顾你  保护你吗
Nobody to look after you, protect you?
我不需要  自己能行
I don't need, I can do myself.
那好吧
Alright then,
那我们一起去公寓看看吧
Do we go with the flat?
让我考虑一下
I must think.
听你的
You do that.
来个口活吧
How about a blow job?
让我爽爽行不
It would make me very happy.
可以吗
Well?
我花钱  你受益
My loss, your gain.
你在想什么啊
What are you thinking?
我咋能让你干这个
Would I really do that with you?
来  起来吧
C'mon, get up.
在我眼里你可不是鸡
To me you're not a whore.
只是开个玩笑
I was just kidding.
好好考虑
You think about it,
我会照顾你的
And I'll look after you.
你可以相信我
You can trust me.
你能有大出息
You can make something of yourself.
不错  真准
Nice. Great.
这4发都很准
These four were great.
这发太快  慢慢来
Too fast on this one. Take your time.
扣扳机的手指放松
Easy with the trigger finger.
多谢
Thank you.
下一发
Next please.
装弹
Load.
别专心过头了
Stop concentrating so hard.
开始射击
Commence firing.
今天也要值夜勤吗
You've got night duty today?
你要干什么
What are you going to do?
在家待着
Stay home.
老豪斯勒还在开车
Look, old Hausner is still driving.
我们该向上面报告他
We should alert the authorities.
他没办法  全靠自己
He has to, he's all alone.
要是出事怎么办
What if something happens?
你现在没当班
You're not on duty.
真遗憾
Unfortunately not.
嘿
Hey there.
瞧谁来了
Well, look who came to visit.
老妈打电话了
Mom called.
她想把我送到收养所去
She wants to put me in a home.
她让我来看看你是否需要帮助
She said to see if you need some help.
我自己过的好得很
I do fine on my own.
她让我给你砍柴
She said to cut your firewood.
小子  你还认我真是奇怪呀
I'm surprised you still know me.
你想跟我井水不犯河水吗
You didn't want anything to do with me.
你错过了葬礼
You missed the funeral.
当时我脱不开身
I couldn't make it.
连葬礼都脱不开身吗
Even missed the funeral.
我在坐牢  他们不让我去参加葬礼
I was in jail, they don't let you go to funerals.
那你就不该偷盗
Then you shouldn't have stolen.
今天我没多少时间
I don't have much time today.
我得回去工作
I have to get back to work.
-你有工作了吗  -对
- You have a job? - Yes.
好吧  那进来吧
Alright, come in then.
葬礼相当特别
It sure was special.
整个墓地人山人海
The whole cemetery full of people.
神父
And the priest...
念的悼词也很优美
Spoke such beautiful words.
我该走了
I should get going.
她真的很有人缘
She was real popular.
今天我有点忙
I'm kind of in a hurry today.
真有人缘
Real Popular.
下周或是下下周  我再来吧
I'll come by next week or the week after.
你想咋的就咋的
Do what you want.
我总能填饱肚子的
I reckon there will be something to eat.
-不好意思  -没关系
- Sorry. - That's ok.
再见
Bye.
是我孙子  阿莱克斯
That's Alex, my grandson.
你还有孙子  我都不知道
You have a grandson? I didn't know that.
对  他住城里
Yes. He lives in the city.
城里人要么自以为是  要么是泼皮无赖
In the city you end up arrogant or a scoundrel.
他是后者
He ended up a scoundrel.
我打算载你出去
I was thinking I could pick you up...
我们可以一起开车去教堂
And we could drive to church together.
你觉得我老的都开不了车了吗
You think I'm too old to drive?
住在同村却开两辆车很不划算
It's silly to drive from the same village in two cars.
您的投资期限是多久
How long do you want to invest it?
也许是6到7年
Maybe six or seven years...
如果有什么更好的收益
If there's any advantage.
当然有  但是不多
There is, but it's not much.
区别在于4%和4.25%
The difference is 4%,4.25%...
不过您可能对这更感兴趣
But you might be interested in this...
喂食时间
Feeding time.
时间快到了
It's about time.
安琪
Well, angel.
你考虑过了吗
Have you thought about it?
好  那明天我带你去看公寓
Good, then I'll show you the flat tomorrow.
我还是想在这儿工作
I refer to work here.
不想在公寓工作
Not in flat.
不想
No?
但是你能多赚点钱啊
But you'll earn more.
我想和其他女孩儿在一起  这样比较好
I refer to stay with other girls. better.
胡说  再好好想想
Nonsense. keep thinking.
明天我们去看公寓
Tomorrow we'll go see the flat.
你知道你的问题出在哪儿吗
You know what your roblem is?
不知道  我有什么问题
No. do I have one?
你太温和了
You're too soft.
你想粗暴一点  但个性却并非如此
You want to be tough, but you're not.
人们很快就能看出来
Peole can tell immediately.
其实你不是那种人  这就是你的问题
You don't really belong. that's your problem.
太温和
Too soft.
公寓怎么样
Well, what's the flat like?
比旅馆强点儿
Better than hotel.
你接受那个工作了吗
You taking it?
没有
No.
那你和他说了吗
Did you tell him?
他说什么了
What did he say?
他说让我再考虑考虑
He say to keep thinking.
他想和你做爱吗
Did he want to fuck?
说实话
Tell the truth.
你干什么
What is this?
没装子弹
It's not loaded.
你干什么  拿开
What is this? put away!
没装子弹
It's not loaded.
你吓着了  是吗
You were scared, right?
你吓坏了
You were scared.
-你干吗这么做  -我心里很乱
- Why you do that? - I'm just messing around.
我在打银行的主意
I'm doing a bank.
什么意思  "打银行的主意"
What means "i doing bank?"
我走进去  掏出枪来
I go in, show them the gun,
他们非常害怕  我拿了钱  就出来
They shit bricks, I take the money, and walk out.
胡说
Bullshit.
然后还了你的债咱们就去西班牙
Then we pay your debts and go to spain.
胡说
Bullshit.
他们会找到你把你扔进监狱的
They find you and you go back in jail.
会这样的
That will happen.
他们抓不到我的  因为我有周密的计划
They won't catch me because I have a plan.
我了解那个银行  也找到了脱身路线
I know the bank, I have an escaep route.
-到国外  -你别干  真是胡说
- Out in the country... - you don't do! is bullshit.
我们得做点事儿  不能就这样下去
We have to do something, we can't go on like this.
什么不能这样下去
What not go on like this?
不是一切都很正常吗
Is all perfectly normal.
我们发现了金龟子
we found a beetle!
闹腾
Suer.
他打开门跑进树林中
Then he opened the door and ran into the woods...
我们紧跟着  很快就捉住了他
With us on his heels. we caught him fast.
他吓得屁滚尿流
It was ok, he was scared shitless.
大喊着别开枪
Please don't shoot!
像水手那样咒骂着
And cussing like a sailor. picko, picko!
但你不知道
But you never know.
他要是有枪会怎么样  我怕这样的人
What if he has a gun? man was I scared!
那次行动时  正好我没当班
For once we get some action, and I'm off duty.
你本来也抓不住他  太慢了
You wouldn't have caught him anyway. too slow.
谁慢了
Who's slow?
干杯
Cheers!
感谢你的邀请
Thanks for inviting us.
什么时候生
When is it due?
随时
Any day now.
休伯特跟我说你流过产
Hubert told me you miscarried.
三个月的时候
In my third month.
肯定很可怕
Must be horrible.
我好怕也碰到这种事儿
I was so scared that would happen to me.
我们真蠢  婴儿房都布置好了
We're so stupid, we already finished the nursery.
谢了
Thanks.
可能我们到头来还得收养孩子
Maybe we should adopt after all.
苏西  我们能自己解决
Susi, no. it'll work out.
要有点儿耐心
We just have to be patient.
我们够耐心的了
We've been patient so long.
也许这次能中呢
Maybe it worked this time.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
女人的直觉
A woman feels that kind of thing.
收养也会带来问题的
Look, adotion just causes problems later.
孩子不是我们的
The kid isn't ours,
从别人那儿来
It's from just anybody.
不知道是什么样的性格
There's no way of predicting his character.
你没法知道
You just can't know.
你说得对
You're right.
你要做什么
What you doing?
-离开那儿  -不
C'mon, get out of there! - no.
-请别这样  -你大叫什么
-Please not! - why are you yelling?
别叫了  听话
Stop yelling and obey!
听话
Obey!
你滚蛋
And you, fuck off!
-你要来真的吗  -你疯了吗
-Are we getting nervous? - are you crazy?
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
镇静点  你们俩
Calm down, all!
冷静点
Stay cool.
是你让我给她点颜色看看
You tell me to soften her u...
这人是新来的
The man is new around here,
他还不知道是怎么回事儿呢
He doesn't know how things work yet.
请你原谅他
You gotta excuse him.
事实上我该向你道歉
No actually I owe you an aology.
这是我的损失  你的收获
My loss, your gain.
所幸哈里是个老朋友
Good thing harry's an old friend.
一个绅士
A gentleman.
我想他不会记仇的
I'm sure he's willing to forget everything.
我们一会儿再谈
We'll talk about that later.
现在  你得道歉
Now, you aologize!
-我听着呢  -抱歉
- I hear that. - sorry.
正式地道个歉
C'mon, do it properly.
握手
Shake hands.
对不起  我不是有意的
Sorry, I didn't mean it.
现在把安琪带到旅馆里
Now take our angel to the hotel,
她今天可以收工了
She can call it a day.
你也不许再犯任何错误
And no more mistakes from you!
闭嘴吧
Shut up!
塔玛拉  他怂恿那人打你
Tamara, he aid him to break you.
我当时在场  他们像好朋友那样聊天
I was there. they talked like best friends.
他对我大喊大叫
He bawled me out.
让我道歉
Made me aologize.
他为什么这样做
Why he do it?
是啊  为什么
Yeah, why?
你怎么想
Why do you think?
到这儿来  宝贝儿
Come here.
我出去走走
Hello. I take walk.
怎么可能一个大活人进出
How can someone go in and out,
却没人注意到呢
And no one notices a thing?
她什么也没带
She had nothing on her.
只说出去走走
Said she was taking a walk.
那怎么她的房间空空如也了呢
Then why is her room cleared out?
不知道  她只是出去走走
I don't know. she went for a walk.
你不知道吗
You don't know?
啥都不知道  我干嘛花钱雇你个白痴呢
What do I pay you idiots for if you don't know anything?
我没离开过前台
I never left the front desk.
她就是出去走走
She was just taking a walk.
但是她跑了
But now she's gone.
带着行李  对吧
Along with her luggage, right?
对不对
Right?
-你跟她说什么了吗  -没有
- Did you say anything to her? - no.
我又不傻
I'm not stupid.
她还欠我这个月的租金呢  500块
She still owes me this month's rent, 500.
现在谁来付啊
Who's going to pay that now?
想让我告诉你们吗
Want me to tell you?
我要从你们的工资里扣
I'm deducting it from your wages,
一人一半儿
Half each.
听明白了吗
You got that?
我们走
C'mon, let's go!
你怎么这么快就回来了
Why you back so soon?
收拾东西  我们得走
Pack your things! we gotta go.
-为什么  -我稍后解释
- Why? - I'll explain later.
我们去哪儿
Where we going?
先住旅馆吧  我也不知道
To a hotel, I have no idea.
-他有所怀疑  -是的  问题就在这儿
- Does he suspect? - yes. that's the problem.
快点儿  他们来了
Please hurry up. they're coming.
谁来了
Who's coming?
你想还能是谁
Who do you think?
快点儿吧  出租车等着呢
Hurry up please! the taxi is waiting.
我们现在怎么办
What we do now?
起床  我们去吃点儿早餐
C'mon, let's grab some breakfast.
我好害怕
I'm scared.
不会有问题的
Nothing can go wrong.
我有种不太好的预感
I have bad feeling.
最好还是别干了
Better to not do it.
只有没有计划的笨蛋才会被抓住
Only idiots without a plan get caught.
我认识个人他
I know a guy who...
还要别的吗
Anything else?
不会有问题的  别害怕了
Nothing can go wrong. don't be scared!
我不想坐这儿干等
I don't want to wait here.
不会很久的  就几个小时
It won't take long, just a few hours.
我跟你一块儿去
I come with you.
塔玛拉  别傻了  你帮不上忙
Tamara, that's silly, you can't help me.
那我在外面等
I wait outside.
塔玛拉  怎么了
Tamara, why?
别犯傻了
It's silly.
不会有问题的
Nothing can go wrong.
我进去  他们给我钱  然后我们就走
I go in, they give me the money, and we slit.
但是你不能开枪
But you must not shoot.
我开不了抢  它没装子弹
I can't shoot, it's not loaded.
-我说过多少次了  -你保证
- How many times do I have to say it? - promise!
它没装子弹
It's not loaded.
没装子弹
Not loaded.
现在如何
Now what?
干了
We do it.
不会有问题的
Nothing can go wrong.
我一会儿就回来
I'll be right back.
趴到地上
On floor!
都放进去
All.
趴到地上
On floor!
都装进去
Aii.
那些也装上
There too.
快点儿
Faster!
现在趴到地上
Now, on floor!
早上好  这儿不能停车  你得开走
Morning. this is a no standing zone. you'll have to leave.
你可以到主道上
But if you go to the main square,
那儿有很多停车位
There's plenty of parking there.
我男友快回来了
My boyfriend be right back.
他人呢
Where is your boyfriend?
去购物了
Had to make shopping.
有身份证吗  护照也行
Do you have some ID, maybe a passort?
也在我男友那儿
My boyfriend also has.
你打哪来的
Where are you from?
乌克兰
Ukraine.
男友呢
And your boyfriend?
不知道
I don't know.
什么  不知道
What, you don't know?
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
-趴下  -我不会伤害你的
- On floor! - I won't hurt you.
趴着别动
Don't move.
他开枪了
He fired.
各警员注意
Calling all units,
大众银行被抢  一名疑犯身上有枪
Bank robbery at the Volksbank. one suspect, armed...
请求支援
come in please.
Gfohl twenty, come in please.
他刚开枪了
He just opened fire.
打破了后窗玻璃
Shattered our rear window.
别怕  他们逮不着我们
Don't be scared. they won't catch us.
他们逮不着我们
They won't catch us.
塔玛拉
Tamara
塔玛拉  你怎么了
Tamara, what's wrong?
怎么了
What is it?
你被打中了吗
Did he hit you?
塔玛拉  说话啊
Say something, Tamara!
有人吗
Isn't anyone here?
是你啊
Ah, it's you.
大白天还睡觉
Sleeping in broad daylight?
没  有点困  打了个盹
No, I felt a little dizzy, so I lay down.
-准备来劈柴了吗  -是的
- Here to chop wood already? - Yeah.
想干来着
I wanted to,
可我车突然抛锚了
But my motorcycle broke down.
突然抛锚
What do you mean broke down?
发动机坏了
The engine died.
我徒步过树林到这儿的
So I came through the woods on foot.
来杯杜松子酒怎样
You want some schnapps?
不用了
No.
能借下你的车吗
Can you lend me your car?
借车干吗
My car?
去维也纳办点事
I have to go to Vienna, straighten things out.
我的车  不借
My car? I don't know.
放心  不久  就几小时
Take care of things. I won't be long, a few hours.
晚上就回
I'll be back tonight.
发动机咋了
What's wrong with the engine?
有心事吗
What's wrong?
什么  能有啥事
What? what could be wrong?
我哪知道
How should I know?
没啥  一切顺利
Nothing, everything's fine.
晚饭快好了
Dinner's almost ready.
拜托  罗伯特  快说
C'mon, Robert, tell me.
-说啥  -准有事  我看得出来
- What? - Something's wrong, I can tell.
快说出来吧
C'mon, out with it.
真没啥  倒霉的一天  就这样
It's nothing special, rough day, that's all.
银行抢劫
Bank robbery.
啥  在我们村里
What, in our village?
抢匪揣着近5万欧元跑了
They got away with almost 50,000 euros.
天哪
My goodness!
我碰巧撞见抢匪
I ran into them by chance and...
想逮捕他们
Tried to detain them,
可他们跳上车跑了
But they jumped in the car and were gone.
被你撞见了
You ran into them?
碰巧
By chance.
-他们有家伙吗  -有
- Were they armed? - Yeah.
天哪
Oh my gosh.
没那么糟  我们会逮倒他们的
It's not that bad. we'll catch them eventually.
你撞见了疑犯
You ran into armed suspects,
为何现在才告诉我
And you didn't tell me until now?
没事发生
Nothing happened.
抢匪人多吗
Were there a lot of them?
一男一女
A man and a woman.
行了  你撞见抢匪
Ok, you ran into them,
他们威胁你了吗
And did they threaten you?
别说了  很高兴我已经下班了
Let's drop it. I'm glad to be off-duty now.
就像我说的  没事发生
And like I said, nothing happened.
我去接
I'll get it.
我是卡戈  您找哪位
Kargl, hello?
是的  他在
Yes, he's here.
罗伯特  找你的
Robert, it's for you.
是我  啥事
Yes?
好  马上来  给我25分钟
Yes, I'll be right there. in about 25 minutes.
是  好的
Yes, alright.
怎么了
What happened?
我得去趟州警署
I have to go to the State Police Office.
现在  为什么
Now? why?
他们找到那辆逃车了
They found the getaway car.
就为这你得去市里
You have to go to the city for that?
稍后我再向你解释
I'll explain it to you later.
是的  就是她
Yes, that was her.
确定吗
No doubt in your mind?
她是谁
And who is she?
没身份证
No ID on her.
我甚至怀疑她都没注册过
I doubt she was even registered.
他俩或许为钱大吵
Maybe they argued about money,
抢银行的就把她打死了
And the bank robber shot her.
从后面  透过后窗吗
From behind? through the rear window?
用只格洛克手枪  不可能
With a glock? no.
我瞄的是轮胎
I aimed at the tires.
是啊  是有这种烂事发生的
Yeah, shit happens.
今天你有访客吗
You have a visitor today?
是啊  他叫阿莱克斯
Yes, Alex.
他来劈柴的
He's chopping wood.
-我们见过一面  -真的吗
- We met once. - Really?
是的  简单地说在农场门口
Yes, briefly at the farm, in the doorway.
-想必你一定高兴  -没错
- You must be glad. - Ye.
听说昨天抢劫的事了吗
Hear about the robbery yesterday?
啥抢劫
What robbery?
有人抢了银行
They robbed the bank.
我们的银行吗
Our bank?
被罗伯特撞见了  想不到吧
Robert ran into them, just imagine!
他试着逮抢匪  可他们有家伙
He tried to detain them. they were armed.
-我真不想想这事  -罗伯特
- I hate to think about it. - Robert?
-他受伤了吗  -没  感谢上帝
- Was he hurt? - No, thank god.
有人死了
There was a casualty,
明天接你时再告诉你
I'll tell you tomorrow when I pick you up.
这些我最爱吃
I like these best.
她丈夫是警察吗
Is her husband a policeman?
黄油我们也要
We need butter too.
-明天和我们一起去吗  -去哪儿
- Are you coming with us tomorrow? - Where?
做礼拜
It's Sunday.
不了  我继续干活
No, I'll keep working.
不会害你的
It sure wouldn't hurt you.
我出去散步
I'm going for a walk.
-天快黑了  -没关系
- It'll be dark soon. - Doesn't matter.
他觉得夜里散步很正常
He thinks it's normal to go for a walk in the dark.
他们在调查枪的使用
Now they are investigating the use of firearms,
看我是否属正当开枪
Checking whether it was justified...
废话  当然正当
Of course it was!
他们下了控诉
And they filed a complaint.
控诉你吗
Against you?
谁干的
Who did?
区警署
District Police Office.
控诉你什么
For what?
过失杀人
Manslaughter.
他们还真敢
The nerve of them!
你冒着生命危险  他们却起诉你
You risk your life and they file a comlaint!
还是自己人
Your own peole.
这就是制度
That's the system.
多"好"的制度
A fine system!
知道抢匪身份了吗
Do they know who they were?
仍无头绪
Still no leads.
外国人  俄罗斯或波兰的
Foreigners. Russians or Poles.
或许是非法入境者
Maybe illegal aliens.
她可能是鸡
She might have been a prostitute.
谢天谢地
Good riddance!
他没表露  可压力不小啊
He doesn't show it, but it's a huge strain.
这也难怪  她死了
No wonder, she's dead.
糟透了
It's awful.
他一直惦着  我去去就回
He thinks about it constantly. I'll be right back.
别烦了  他无心的
Don't let him get to you, he has no idea.
什么
What?
你爸不知道事情有多严重
Your dad doesn't see how hard this is.
是啊  我老爸就这样
Yeah, you know how he is.
我只是冰些啤酒
I'm just cooling some beer.
矿泉水也快没了
We're almost out of mineral water too.
再说  事情没那么糟
Besides, it's not that bad.
她死了  我能怎么办
So she's dead. what was I supposed to do?
只能怪运背
It was just bad luck.
你也无能为力
There's nothing you can do.
老爸就这样  让他说吧
You know him. just let him talk.
-我去拿甜点  -好的
- I'll get dessert. - Fine.
猜我碰见谁了  西尔维娅·斯陶戴彻
You know who I ran into? Sylvia Staudacher.
她生了对双胞胎女儿
She has twins. girls.
她们忒可爱了
They are so cute.
是啊  很可爱
Yes, they're adorable.
你们俩呢
What about you?
就你俩更好是吧
What could be better for the two of you right now!
-又不是刻意不生  -房子都有了
- It wasn't meant to be. - House is done.
你30多了  生孩子的绝佳时期
You're over 30, the perfect age.
没错  妈妈  我们在试
Yes, mama, we're trying,
可你不能硬逼
But you can't force it.
如有孩子  罗伯特就会忘却悲伤
It would get Robert's mind off...
是的  我知道  我俩都想要孩子
Yes, I know. we want kids.
事实上  生孩子可能性极小
It's highly unlikely, if you want to know the truth.
为啥  你怀过孕啊
Why? you were just pregnant.
那显然是极走运的一次
Incredible luck, apparently.
纯属意外
A fluke.
难以置信
I can't believe that.
做检查了吗
Did you get tested?
出啥问题了
And what's the problem?
问题不在我
It's not me.
那么  是罗伯特吗
Then what, Robert?
简直难以置信  他那么猛
Now that I really can't believe! he's so athletic.
那么多啊
That's quite a pile!
我估计你得花一个月
You'll need a month for that I reckon.
-一周  -真的吗  就一周
- A week. - Really, just a week.
我光看都看累了
I get tired just looking at that pile.
豪斯纳在哪儿
Where is Hausner?
他没在屋里吗
Isn't he inside?
没去看
I didn't check.
我打赌有你帮他  他定高兴极了
Bet he's glad someone's helping him.
农场就他孤身一人  真替他可怜
I feel sorry for him alone on the farm.
他来了
Here he is.
你来啦
You're here already.
那走吧
Then let's go.
他不会去  他从小就不信上帝
He's not coming, born and bred a heathen.
真高兴他能为你工作
Be glad he's doing your work for you.
不知道我是否还会弹
I don't know if I can still play.
别耍赖  你必须弹  你承诺过的
No fair, you have to play now. you romised.
太久没弹了
It's been so long.
有些事情你一辈子也不会忘
Some things you never forget.
豪斯纳要为我们弹奏一曲
Hausner is going to play for us.
他弹得很起劲
He really played up a storm.
他很久没那么高兴了  简直像变了个人
Hasn't been that happy for ages, he's like a new man.
我想他很乐意有人在农场陪他
I think he enjoys having someone on the farm.
你会呆一阵子吧
Are you staying a while?
不  把柴砍完我就走
No, just long enough to finish the firewood.
我想我得走了
I guess I'll be going.
祝你愉快  高兴点儿
Have fun. Fun...
祝你好运
Good luck.
你丈夫不去教堂吗
Your husband doesn't go to church?
他并不热衷此事  他更愿意"走他的路"
He doesn't hold much stock in it, he'd rather run his route.
他的路
His route?
去池塘  然后回来
To the pond and back.
天天如此
Every day.
你好
Hi.
我再弹一遍
I'm playing again.
你想她吗
Do you miss her?
独自工作
The work alone!
令人沮丧
It's depressing alright.
但我还会见到她的
But I'll see her again.
不久就会
It won't be long now.
你会再见到她
You'll see her again?
她在等我
She's waiting.
你为什么不给我打电话
Why didn't you call?
打电话  为什么要打
Call? why should I?
都凌晨1点多了  我却不知道你在哪儿
It's past 1 a.m., I didn't know where you were.
我不会出事的
Well, nothing happened.
但我还是担心
I still get worried.
我和别的警官在一起
I was with the other officers.
我们一直在聊天  连时间都忘了
We were talking. I lost track of time.
-聊什么  -抱歉
- About what? - I'm sorry.
聊些什么
Talking about what?
你们聊了些什么
What did you talk about?
没什么特别的  关于工作和最近发生的事
Nothing special. About work and what happened.
你跟别人聊天  为何不跟我聊
You talk to the other men, why not to me?
说了你也不明白
You don't understand anyway.
你要是跟我说了  没准我会明白
Maybe if you talked to me I would.
另外  那些人知道这是意外  只是不走运
Besides, the men know it was an accident. bad luck.
难道我不知道吗
And I don't know that?
那你为何要用那种眼神看我
Then why do you look at me that way?
什么  哪种眼神
What? How do I look at you?
你以为我不知道你是怎么想的吗
You think I can't tell what you're thinking?
你以为我不知道吗
You think I can't tell?
我是怎么想的
What am I thinking?
是我射杀了她
That I shot her.
你觉得那是我的错
I can tell you think it's my fault.
什么
What?
你想谈谈  想让我为自己辩解  对吗
You want to talk? Want me to justify myself?
尽管如此  你仍旧不会相信我
Even though you don't believe me.
你刚才的话不是认真的  对吗
You weren't really serious in there, were you?
不是  忘了那些话吧
You're right, forget it.
你不会真的认为我是那么想的吧
You don't really believe that's what I think.
不会
You're right.
想上床睡觉吗
Are you coming to bed?
我想先把啤酒喝完
I'm just going to finish my beer.
好吧
Okay.
苹果也快熟了
The apples are just about ripe too.
给
Here,
尝尝这个
Taste this.
喜欢吗
Well? like it?
是啊  还不错
Yeah, not bad.
冬天最大的好处就是  苹果到处都是
The best winter apples far and wide.
你在为谁演奏
Who are you playing for?
豪斯纳一开始演奏  就停不下了
When Hausner gets started, there's no stopping him.
她给我们带蛋糕来了
She brought us a cake.
你刚才吓到我了
Did you scare me!
豪斯纳不让我走
Hausner wouldn't let me go.
他能再弹琴真是太好了  那是他最喜欢的
It's great he's playing again. It's what he loves most.
你想从我们这儿得到什么
What do you want from us?
你什么意思  我什么也不想要
What do you mean? Nothing.
你为什么来这儿  你想要什么
Why do you come here? what do you want?
我只想让他高兴
I figure it makes him happy.
看他在农场上孤独生活  我很同情
I feel sorry for him on the farm all alone...
他不会再孤独了
He's not alone anymore.
你假装我们认识彼此似的
You act like we know each other.
我们认识彼此吗
Do we know each other?
不
No.
我们并不认识彼此  而且最好不要认识
We don't know each other. and it's better that way.
你是不是太粗鲁了
Well aren't you uncouth!
你把事情搞得一团糟
You're turning things upside down.
我希望你离我们远点儿
I want you to leave us alone.
蛋糕  音乐  舞蹈  这些我都不想要
Cake, music, dance, I don't want it.
我希望你不要回来
I don't want you coming back.
可以吗
Do you think that's possible?
那来我家好了
Then come to my house.
今晚我独自在家
I'll be alone tonight.
如果你想来的话
If you want.
天黑以后  从后面进来  就不会被看到了
Wait till it's dark, come around the back so no one sees you.
如果你真想来
If you want.
你没有退缩
You didn't chicken out.
进来
Come in.
如果我令你感到惊讶  这一点也不奇怪
I wouldn't be surprised if you were surprised at me.
我对自己也感到惊讶
I'm surprised at myself.
喝杯酒吗
Glass of wine?
白酒还是红酒  我都有
White or red? I've got both.
随便
Whatever.
我更喜欢白酒  红酒让人昏昏欲睡
I prefer white, red makes you sleepy.
白酒让人振奋
White perks you up.
那就白酒吧
White's ok.
马上就好  我去开瓶新的
Be right back. New bottle.
这瓶刚才并不满  不像你想的那样
It wasn't full, though. Not that you think...
请坐  别拘束
Sit. make yourself comfortable.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
希望你能喜欢
Well, I hope you like it.
我觉得这酒很不错  它我们的必备酒
I think it's quite good. It's our house wine.
好吧  干杯
Well then, cheers!
坐吧
Have a seat.
房子真漂亮
Nice house.
谢谢  看起来是挺漂亮的
Thanks. It turned out nice.
警察挣钱很多吗
Do cops earn this much?
不  我开了家商店  双职工
No, I've got the store, double income.
我们攒了不少  还有罗伯特和他朋友的
We did a lot ourselves, Robert and his friends, that is.
我们还从双方父母和银行借了点钱
And we got money from our parents and the bank.
他们拥有房屋的一半产权  楼上归他们
It owns half the house, the upstairs floor.
不过  那没关系
But that's ok.
再过几年就还清了
It's just for a few years.
每件物品都很整洁  干净
Everything neat. clean.
很好
Tip top.
没错  要知道  我想要个舒适的家
Yeah, you know, you want it to be cozy.
坐吧
Have a seat.
房子很漂亮
Nice house.
老公也很好
Good husband.
一切都很完美
Everything perfect.
尽如人意阿
Exactly as it should be.
你肯定很幸福
You must be happy.
是的  我想是
Yes, I guess.
当然是  我没什么好抱怨的
Sure, I can't complain.
那你为何还想上我
So why do you want to fuck me?
我猜这是个愚蠢的想法
I guess it was a stupid idea.
我还没想得那么远  抱歉
I didn't really think that far, sorry.
-等等  -等什么
- Wait. - For what?
-我能冲个凉吗  -上楼向右转
- Can I take a shower? - Upstairs on the right.
还想喝一杯吗
Another glass of wine?
好的
Yeah.
真舒服
How cozy!
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
你已经厌烦你的警官了吗
Are you bored with your cop already?
不  他是我丈夫
No, he's my husband.
我只是想做
I just wanted to.
上帝会对你说些什么啊
What does your God have to say?
他能理解我
He understands.
真是个善解人意的上帝
A very understanding God.
你什么意思
What is it?
你就不能友善点吗
Can't you just be friendly?
像正常人那样的举动会让你丢脸吗
Will you lose face acting like a normal person?
你经历过什么事
What happened to you?
你有孩子吗
Do you have kids?
没有
No.
但楼上有个儿童房
But you have a nursery upstairs.
但我们没有孩子
But we don't have any.
我要走了
I'll be going.
你为什么总这样  有人对你做过什么吗
Why are you this way? What did anyone do to you?
你最好还是不知道
Be glad you don't know everything.
你还会来吗
Will you come again?
你干活的确是把好手
You sure can work.
真该给你些奖励
Got to give you credit for that.
你该结婚了
You should get married.
男人需要女人  否则他会变蠢的
A man needs a woman or he gets folly.
以你的工作方式  找个女人应该很容易
You'll find one easily the way you work.
你觉得伐木会吸引女人吗
You think chopping wood impresses women?
她们会格外关注能干的男人
They notice a man who can work.
即使现在也一样
Won't be any different nowadays.
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - Hi.
怎么了
What's wrong?
有点头晕
Just dizzy.
你经常会这样吗
Does this happen often?
是的  有时会
Yeah, sometimes.
把止痛药递给我  好吗
Can you hand me the bag balm?
它对头痛很有效
It works wonders for headaches.
你也会头痛吗
You have headaches too?
一直都这样
All the time.
你应该去做个检查
You should go in for a checkup.
医生也无能为力
Doctors don't know anything either.
看医生又不会有坏处
But it can't hurt.
就是有点头痛  不必看医生
I don't need a doctor for a little headache.
真是个顽固的老白痴
You're a stubborn old fool.
你自己也是个顽固的白痴
You're a stubborn fool yourself.
谁会照看牛群和农场呢
Who will look after the cows and the farm?
我不会离开
I'm not leaving.
最后  他们可以把我抬走
They can carry me out in the end.
到那时就不是我的问题了
It won't be my problem anymore.
但在那之前  我决不离开
But until then, I'm not budging.
直到最后
Till the end.
今天就一个人吗
Alone today?
豪斯纳怎么了
How's Hausner?
他很好
He's ok.
替我向他问好
Tell him I said hi.
我今晚还是独自一人
I'll be alone again tonight.
罗伯特  过来  为我儿子干一杯
Hey Robert, c'mon! Let's drink to my son.
也给他来一杯  你要吗
Give him a glass, would you?
祝贺你  -谢谢
Congratulations. - thanks!
20.5英尺  6.8磅  黑发
20.5 inches, 6.8 ibs, black hair.
-过来喝杯酒  -我在值班
-Here, have a drink. - I'm on duty.
不要每件事都这么认真
Stop taking everything so seriously.
把杯子递给我  谢谢
Pass me my glass! thanks.
他昨天3点过来  花了好长时间
He came at 3 yesterday. took forever.
-你一整天都在吗  -当然
-You were there the whole time? - of course.
你总是吓我一跳
You're always scaring me.
快进来  别让人看见了
Come in, what if someone sees you?
我刚才还想你不会来了
I was sure you weren't coming.
我的直觉不行  幸好我也从不和人打赌
Good thing I didn't bet anything.
你总是和狼一样独来独往
Have you always been a lone wolf, coming and going...
抱歉  不过那就是我对你的印象
Sorry, but that's my impression of you.
我不总那样
No. not always.
等处理完这的事后  你就回维也纳吗
Will you go back to vienna when you're done?
你有女友吗  我对你一无所知
You have a girlfriend? I know nothing about you.
有一个  不过最近
I had one until recently.
你们结束了吗
It's over?
出了什么事
What happened?
她被杀了
She was murdered.
什么
What?
她被人杀了
She was murdered.
-我的天哪  -那个杀人凶手
-Oh my goodness. - and the man who did it...
活得好好的
Lives on.
和什么都没发生一样
Just like always.
丝毫没有愧疚
He couldn't care less.
-那不是真的吧  -那就是真的
-That can't be true. - but it is.
凶手好好地活着
He goes on living his life.
而她却死了
And she is dead.
我现在所想的就是要改变这一切
And all I ever think about is that I have to change that.
那凶手不会有好日子过的
He can't simly go on living.
你想知道发生了什么  现在你知道了
You wanted to know what's wrong, now you know.
你不能那样做  连想都不能想
You can't do that. you mustn't even think it.
不能什么
What?
为了复仇杀人
Killing someone out of vengeance.
我知道你不信教  但这是有罪的
I know you don't believe, but it's a sin.
你不能这么做
You mustn't do it.
现在我能理解你了
Now I understand you.
这就是为什么你这么冷酷
That's why you're so cold.
这么残忍
So brutal.
冷酷
Cold?
答应我
You mustn't do it.
你不会杀人的
Promise me.
现在我能够理解你了
Now I understand you.
过来
C'mon.
你现在得走了  罗伯特回来了
You have to go, robert came home.
偷偷溜出去  不要让他看到你
Find your way out. don't let him see you.
也许他倒想见我
Maybe he'd like to meet me.
不要这样  快走吧  不要毁了这一切
Please don't. please go. don't ruin everything.
快走吧
Please go.
怎么这个时候已经到家了
Why are you home already?
出什么事了
What's wrong?
罗伯特  怎么回事
Robert, what haened?
他们让我休假
They gave me a leave of absence.
休假
Leave of absence?
说我不宜执勤
I'm unfit for duty.
咨询师说这种状态很正常
The counselor said it's perfectly normal.
发生这种事理所应当会有此反应
It's a normal reaction to the events.
确实是这样
Sure it is.
他还说我需要心理治疗
And he said I might need psychological help.
我没病  我很正常  遇到这种事每个人都会这样
I'm not sick, it's normal. it's how anyone would react.
这是当然的
That's absolutely right.
-我瞄的是轮胎  -大伙都知道
-I aimed at the tires. - everyone knows you did.
我一直是百发百中
I normally hit my mark,
我也不知道为什么会射偏
I don't know how this could happen.
只是运气不好罢了
It was just bad luck.
运气不好
Bad luck.
为什么我这么不走运
Why am I lagued with bad luck?
为什么我总是射不中
Why can't I do anything right?
我觉得心理咨询是个好建议
I think a sychologist is a good idea.
我情不自禁地去看这张该死的照片
And I can't stop looking at the damn photo.
我搞不明白  我不该是现在这样的
I don't understand, it couldn't have been me.
什么照片
What photo?
那女人的
Of the woman.
你有她的照片
You have a photo of her?
你从哪里搞来的
Where did you get this?
我瞄的是轮胎
I aimed at the tires.
你不该再拿着它
You shouldn't have this.
不要再看这张照片了
Shouldn't be looking at it.
现在我去把它扔了  好吗
I'm going to throw it away now. ok?
那我去扔了
I'm throwing the photo away.
怎么了
What's wrong?
现在好点了
I'm ok now.
你该上床休息
You belong in bed.
嗯  也许是吧
Yeah, maybe.
明天我就会好的
I'll be fine tomorrow.
你需要去医院
You need a checkup.
检查身体
At a hospital.
我不在的话  这里会一团糟
Things will fall apart if I'm not here.
所有一切都会不成样子
Everything will go to ruin.
没有东西会不成样子的
Nothing will go to ruin.
我会待在这
I'll stay here.
照看所有东西
I'll keep an eye on everything.
你待在这吗
You'll stay here?
我不会去医院的
I'm not going to any hosital.
进了医院就别想再出去了
They never let you out again,
那里的人会把我送到收养所
And then they put you in a home.
我要留在农场
I'm staying on the farm.
这里的人会带我出去溜达
They can carry me out.
你还没到要死的时候
You're not dying yet.
休息一会儿
Rest a little.
我们过一会儿就走
We'll go in a bit.
我顺便去喂下牛
I'll feed the cows in the meantime.
你好
Hello.
Hi.
-你是豪斯纳的孙子  对吗  -没错
You're hausner's grandson, right? - yeah.
怎么了
And?
你喜欢这里吗
How do you like it here?
这里不是特别有趣  是吗
Not too exciting, is it?
乡村比起城市有点死气沉沉
Pretty dead comared to the city.
不  这挺好的
No, it's fine.
这儿景色不错
Nice spot here.
你就是那个开枪杀人的警察吗
Aren't you the cop who shot that woman?
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
别人都在说
Peole talk.
而且一传十 十传百
And it was in the aper too.
没错
Yes.
我就是
That's me.
那一定很沉痛的经历
Must be a heavy exerience.
我再也不想经历第二次
Wouldn't want to go through it again.
我猜你瞄准的是那个银行劫匪
You aimed at him, the bank robber,
对吗
I guess. am I right?
我瞄准的是汽车轮胎
I aimed at the tires.
打中的却不是
Wanted to.
但我不明白轮胎是很低的
Yeah, but I don't understand. they're much lower.
那时候你肯定瞄得位置太高了
You must have aimed higher for that to happen.
一切发生得太快了
It all went so fast.
我也不清楚那时我怎么想的
I don't understand it myself.
-你会怕那个劫匪吗  -害怕
Aren't you scared of him? - scared?
为什么
Why?
你杀了那个女孩
You killed his girl.
他要是找到你  想开枪杀你呢
What if he tracked you down and wanted to shoot you?
为了复仇
Out of vengeance.
让他来吧
Let him.
随他吧
不过我有一点要问他
But there's one thing I'd ask him.
什么
What?
为什么他一开始要带那女孩去
Why he took her along in the first place.
女孩没有开车协助他逃跑
She wasn't driving, wasn't helping him escae.
他一个人进去抢银行  带着女孩没意义
He went into the bank alone. it doesn't make sense.
他为什么要像郊游一样带着她
Why did he take her as if it were an outing?
整件事的发生是因为女孩无故在那里
The whole mess happened because she was there for no reason.
这就是我要问他的
That's what I'd ask him.
再见
Bye.
晚饭好了
Dinner is ready.
这么丰盛  有什么值得庆祝的吗
What's all this? are we celebrating something?
嗯  或许是
Yes, maybe.
我要告诉你一件事
I have to tell you something.
这事还言之过早  我也不是很确定
It's still too early, and I'm not positive,
可我能感觉到
But I have the feeling...
我觉得终于奏效了
I think it finally worked.
什么
What?
你猜猜
Guess.
你真的这么认为吗
What, you really think so?
你怀孕了吗
That you're pregnant?
嗯
Yes.
有人吗
Hello?
有人在吗
Anyone here?
看来这里还有人
Ah, someone's here after all.
豪斯纳在哪  今天是礼拜天
Where is hausner? it's sunday.
在医院
Hosital.
他怎么了
What's wrong with him?
我不知道  还在检查
We don't know. tests.
真可怜
Poor man.
在他们知道前  你要一直在这吗
You're staying till they know?
总有人要留下来
Someone has to.
-我想和你谈谈  -什么
-I wanted to talk to you. - yeah?
进来说
Come in.
说吧
Let's hear it.
你在池塘边碰到了罗伯特
You ran into robert at the pond.
求你不要告诉他我们之间的事
Please never tell him what we did.
-我为什么要那么做  -答应我
Why should i? - promise me.
对天发誓
Swear it.
我发誓
I swear.
我们两个不要再见面了
We shouldn't see each other anymore.
之前的经历让我很愉快
It was great and electrifying,
但我们还是不要再做那种事了
But we shouldn't do it anymore.
-如果只是偶尔遇见那也行  -纯属偶然的话
-I mean if we meet by chance - perfectly normal.
不过我这样最好
But I think it's better this way.
这是谁
Who's that?
我和你说的那个女孩
The girl I told you about.
那个时候你在那儿
Were you there when...
在她死得时候
When she died?
难道是你
That was you?
什么
What?
是你打劫了银行
You robbed the bank?
你现在打算怎么办
What will you do now?
如果他们没抓到我  我就待在这
Stay here if they don't catch me.
只要他还住在这附近
As long as he's still around.
我必须走了
I have to go now.
不要告诉他我们的事
Please don't tell him what happened.
你不用担心
Don't worry.
我现在真的要走了
I have to go now.